# Delon Takesure Savanhu

## Software Developer (DevOps)

+27625943135 | delon.savanhu@yahoo.com | Johannesburg, South Africa

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Passionate software developer with 7+ years' experience developing applications used by different demographics. I am currently studying for my second honours degree and for the last 2 years, I have been developing the South African Revenue Service eFiling system. I helped Care International Zimbabwe build the ECRAS system from concept to production from 2015 to 2016. I am an avid researcher and team player who enjoys watching crime TV shows and doing personal projects in my spare time.

#### TECH STACK

Front End	JavaScript, ReactJS, CSS3, Bootstrap, HTML5, Xamarin Forms, Angular 2+
Back End	PHP(YII, Symfony & Laravel), ASP WebAPI, ASP .NET Core, .NET(C# & VB.net), APIs, .NET Web Services(WCF), Git, Azure DevOps(Git, Build Pipelines & Test plans), .NET Core APIs, Spring Boot, IBM Web Sphere Messaging Queue, Postman, Jenkins, Docker & Docker Swarm, XML, XSD
Data Stores	MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server
Web Servers	Microsoft IIS, Apache HTTP Server, Apache Tomcat
Operating Systems	Windows 10, Windows Server, Linux Ubuntu Desktop, Linux Ubuntu Server edition, Mac OS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer | iOCO | Johannesburg, South Africa

March 2019 - Current

iOCO is one of Africa's biggest ICT companies, servicing a host of African and middle-eastern countries. The current project I work on, a self service tax portal, services millions of South African tax-payers.

- We moved the eFiling platform to a REST and SOAP based product that can be consumed by web and mobile applications.
- I develop the APIs, Web Services and backend processes.
- Building the application in a tiered architecture that has a database, service and frontend layer meant that the project was decoupled, this led to faster turnaround time when dealing with defects.
- Technologies: C#, Web API, SOAP, IBM WebSphere MQ, VB.net, MSSQL, Angular, Git, Windows Server, IIS web server, Xamarin Forms.

Fullstack Developer | Twenty Third Century Systems | Harare, Zimbabwe

February 2018 – October 2018

Twenty Third Century System is one of Zimbabwe's biggest technology companies providing SAP and bespoke software solutions to the African continent. I worked on a Business-to-business application called Service Exchange that serviced at

least 10000 small to medium businesses in Africa.

- We took over the development of a business-to-business platform called Service Exchange. This platform provides small to medium enterprises with a marketplace to offer their services to other businesses.
- I was a fullstack developer on the project, developing the stored procedures, API, frontend and mobile application.
- We grew the platform from the initial 100s of companies to more than 10000 businesses signing up.
- Technologies: MSSQL stored procedures, C# Web API, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Java Android development, Windows IIS.

Fullstack Developer | UNDP ZRBF | Harare, Zimbabwe

February 2016 - January 2018

The Zimbabwe Resilience Building Fund(ZRBF) is a non-governmental organisation that aims to equip societies in Zimbabwe with the capacity to attain and protect development goals. I worked on the Performance Management System, a platform that records, tracks and reports on project performances.

- I joined the team that was re-doing the Performance Management System from a PHP application to a Microsoft based stack.
- I developed the solution as a fullstack developer, developing both the backend and frontend.
- We successfully migrated from the old PHP based application to a new .Net based application that enabled the staff to easily record, track and report on their respective projects.
- Technologies: ASP.net, MSSQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, Git.

Fullstack Developer | Care International | Harare, Zimbabwe

January 2015 - January 2016

Care International in Zimbabwe is a non-governmental organisation that seeks to alleviate the effects of drought in Zimbabwean communities. I worked on the ECRAS(Enhancing Community Resilience and Sustainability) platform.

- I developed the ECRAS system from concept to production.
- I was responsible for the DevOps on the project: building the application's database, API and frontend upto maintenance of the system.
- We moved the organisation from a paper based reporting system to a computer based system.
- Technologies: ASP.net, MSSQL, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, JQuery, Git.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

Contract Web Developer | Hove Group Investments | Zimbabwe Remote Software Developer | UNDP ZRBF | Remote 2018 March 2016 - April 2016

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science(Hons) Information Technology | Chinhoyi University of Technology | Chinhoyi, Zimbabwe August 2010 – June 2014

• Upper second class, Runner Up: Best ICT project.

Bachelor of Science(Hons) Computing | University of South Africa | South Africa

#### February 2021 - Current

• These are ongoing studies in which I focus on Machine Learning and Artificial intelligence.

## **PUBLICATIONS & AWARDS**

Play Store   AppShare  • https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.afrodeb.appshare	2020
Play Store   PDFUtility  • https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.afrodeb.pdfutility	2020
Web   MediaDownloader  • https://media.afrodeb.com	2020

### **ADDITIONAL ACTIVITIES**

Freelance technical adviser | Pearson Institute | Johannesburg, South Africa

January 2020 - January 2021

## **PROFILES**

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/delon-savanhu/

Github: https://github.com/afrodeb

Play Store: https://play.google.com/store/apps/developer?id=Afrodeb+Studios